liquidity concepts are hard to
understand and beginner Traders
especially find it hard to wrap their
heads around the concepts and even more
advanced Traders they still struggle to
identify and spot liquidity on the
charts why do I think this is the case
well because liquidity is literally
everywhere and just like any other
concept or trading strategy it's
subjective we are all unique Traders
looking at the market through different
lenses trading in different ways
understanding the market in a different
way and according to me just like any
other concept liquidity has to be
systematized you need the system for
identifying liquidity you need to know
your different types of liquidity and
you need to actually Implement liquidity
into your trading strategy so that you
actually know how to use it because
everything that I teach you does not
work on its own it has to be built in a
overall process which is what this video
series is designed to do and in today's
lesson we're gonna do exactly this I'm
gonna teach you how to understand
liquidity Concepts I'm going to show you
the different types of liquidity I use
and I'm gonna teach you how to use them
because again liquidity Concepts will
become easier once you actually know
what you're looking for so that when you
actually see a liquidity pattern on the
charts from the ones that I'm going to
show you're going to be like yes that is
a liquidity area I understand this so
I'm gonna wait for it to get taken so as
always guys grab a pen and paper open an
ocean or a word file get ready to take
notes and please cut out all
distractions and stay with me this is
going to be a relatively short video
compared to the previous ones right so
pay attention watch it till the end and
make sure to also check out the link in
the description download your PDF in
order to facilitate your learning and
without further Ado I hope you're
excited let's get into it
thank you
alright as always we're gonna get
started with an introduction to the
different types of liquidity and of
course first of all we're gonna have a
look at what is actually liquidity then
we're gonna study the different types
with textbook examples with chart
examples and towards the end of the
video we're gonna just jump on the
charts and have a look how you can
actually practice identifying liquidity
on your charts so that should can
actually start seeing it because again
without putting in the work without
actually going to practice a concept
cannot be learned just by watching a
video so let's get into it first of all
again what is liquidity well liquidity
is the ability of a currency pair and
not only current Spirit could be a stock
it could be real estate everything right
uh of an instrument to be traded but or
sold on Demand right so a market is
liquid when there is a constant flow and
participation of buyers and sellers so a
liquid Market is a market when anyone
can come in at any time and sell his
commodity an asset and as you probably
know Forex the Foreign Exchange Market
is one of the most liquid markets and
real estate is one of the most illiquid
markets why well because you can come at
the market you can always buy you can
always sell you can go at your local
currency exchange they're always going
to be able to give you money right or
you can come into the market you can
always open a trade right but with for
example real estate you can't just go
and then buy a property or you can just
go out there and sell a property right
it's pretty illiquid all right so the
concept of liquidity is crucial because
it is pretty much what drives the market
and helps the bfis remember from the
previous lesson execute their orders and
for us retail Traders liquidity is not a
problem as I already mentioned we just
open our platform anytime and we can
take our one to 100 lot contracts and
trades right it's no problem but again
as I told you in the previous lesson is
supply and demand imagine you are a bank
and you open your platform and you try
to place a buy for 10K Lots or contracts
and then like your platform gives you
that mt4 sound right not enough
liquidity to execute your order
right so then what you have to do well
you have to wait or you have to generate
more liquidity Drive price towards those
liquidity pools right and if you can
also remember from the previous uh
lesson remember where the liquidity
actually is right where the stop losses
are where the buy stops are where
usually an exchange of an order happens
and liquidity points are used by the
bfis to get enough counter orders to
theirs so that their order can get
filled again for every buy there needs
to be a sell and for every cell there
needs to be a buy right but if the bank
wants to take 10 000 Lots buy they need
to have 10 000 Lots sell from the other
side so that they can actually fill
their order right and again they do this
by taking other people's stop losses
limit orders stop orders and tricking
them into buying and selling which we're
going to be exploring in this lesson and
again in order to understand liquidity
you need to have a little bit of a
mindset shift because when you see a
double top you are going to be marking
this as a liquidity point when you see
flat chopping price a consolidation
you're always going to be marking it as
a liquidity point and I'm gonna tell you
why in a little bit and also the concept
of a liquidity Gap is very important
because this is like a recharge
mechanism of the market
I bet you haven't never seen a market
that is just keep pushing up and up and
up or down and down down forever right
it usually needs liquidity to recharge
and this is why we always get pullbacks
we get those formations we get liquidity
points and those are pretty much
engineered by the big financial
institutions okay so pretty much imagine
you're going on a trip right now
and you start from Italy and you want to
go to the Netherlands right or maybe you
even want to go to Russia I don't know a
longer trip you can't just start and go
all the way in one go right you're first
gonna stop to get few you're gonna stop
to eat you're gonna stop to sleep right
and just as the market cannot just get
from A to B in one straight move it's
gonna move up it's gonna move down it's
gonna correct it's gonna consolidate
then it's gonna start moving again it's
gonna then start pulling back again all
right this is pretty much grabbing
liquidity okay so that is pretty much
the foundation this is the theorist
right now let's get into some actionable
stuff and I'm gonna show you uh the
liquidity types that I personally use so
as I previously said in the intro there
are many forms of liquidity right you
can look at liquidity in numerous ways
but the key is to always kiss keep it
simple stupid or stupid simple right so
it has to be simple and systematic so
liquidity can be identified above any
high and Below any low why well because
there are stop losses there and and
there are stop orders also there so if
I'm just to give you a very quick
example right well this is the laser so
let me put the pen so I have a push we
have a pullback right the market is
right there so where is the liquidity
well there is liquidity Above This high
and there is liquidity below this low so
as the market goes up and makes a new
high and again after every structure
break what do you usually get after
every structure break
you get a pullback why well because the
market has gathered the liquidity that
was above this High okay and right now
they're retracing back which is a form
of a liquidity grab right so then as
we're here where is the next liquidity
Point well it's either below this low or
above this High okay so then if the
market goes on and actually takes this
liquidity it creates a trend change
right we're now bearish on this market
and what happens next is you start to
correct why well because we collected
all the liquidity that was resting below
the slow so those are pretty much the
single lows and single highs what you
can also have is equal highs and equal
lows and usually you're going to see
them as double tops double bottoms
ranges
um
Penance I don't know triple tops
everything right and I'm actually going
to give you an assignment in a bit I
want you to go and spot all double tops
and double bottoms what you're usually
gonna see is the following if I can only
find my mouse right there it is
we have a double tap right and what the
Mark is usually going to do is something
like this and then you're like oh double
tap I'm gonna short the market but
usually within every double top there is
a spike above and that is when the
market reverses why well because the
stop losses of buyers are right there
right sorry the stop loss of sellers are
right there and the buyers that are
actually looking for the breakout
they're going to be entering buys right
there so you have stop loss of Sellers
and buy stop of buyers so on this fake
move which we had a look at the previous
lesson as that fake move the
manipulation right sellers are stop loss
right and then the buyers are triggering
into the market and this is when we
actually get the real move okay similar
example on the double bottom you get a
double bottom and usually the market is
going to give you like a little reaction
to trick people into buying the market
they have their stop loss below right
and then the market just is a little
Wick boom takes it out and then it
reverses okay so again double tops and
double bottoms are imperfect but this is
because of liquidity okay and when you
see like perfectly equal highs or equal
lows you know that this will eventually
get taken the next type of liquidity is
structural or supply and demand
liquidity so those are old supply and
demand zones or structural Levels by
structural levels we mean higher lows
higher highs lower highs and lower lows
right and those are levels from which
Traders are actually taking trades I'm
gonna show you a textbook example later
another liquidity type I use is a fake
Trend change right what many of you know
as a fake church as well because I see
this concept used a lot the church thing
right so this is pretty much the same
you get a trend change or you get a
charge and then it just gets stop loss
right why because of liquidity and I'm
gonna show you later
the next one is trendline liquidity
which I don't like right that I pretty
much classify this as flat highs and
flat lows right you can have also flags
and channels this is very slow and
correcting price action that is overall
trending okay so again we have if you
want to have a clear Trend usually
you're gonna have like a nice push nice
pullback right but the corrective one it
likes looks something like this right
it's still making hard highs and higher
lows but it's very corrective and then
usually you can draw trend line on the
top on the bottom and then this right
there is going to be your liquidity so
again more examples on that later but
those are the type of liquidity I
personally use right there could be more
you can add imbalance you can add this
you can add that it doesn't matter what
matters is what works for you and what
is actually easy simple and systematic
to understand so
let's cover them one by one
highs and lows liquidity so again as I
previously mentioned every high and
every low has liquidity it could come in
in three ways a single high or low equal
highs or equal lows and uh pretty much
you can have like inducement levels or
an old high note low okay so and I want
you to remember that hard time frame
matters the most a high or a low and a
hard time frame will always matter more
than one on the lower time frame so
let's just have a look at the examples
below right there so
here we have a supply Zone that is
formed the market has pushed away it's
pulling back and then usually what
happens it starts to pull away from the
Zone this singular high is what a lot of
people call inducement but what is this
is just a single high
okay why is this weak why is this
liquidity because if this High fails to
make a new low just like this then it's
weak remember this goes back to the
market structure lesson strong lows
strong highs weak lows weak highs okay
and usually what this does is it tricks
people into selling so people are gonna
sell from here where is their stop loss
above right there pushes pulls back
people are gonna sell from here where is
their stop loss above so what we also
have is like a descending trend line
then the market does the manipulation
comes into the supply Zone and then it
sells off
okay so this is one of the types which
which is also called inducement this is
just like a single high usually they are
located a little tip right there they're
located just below a supply zone or
above a demand Zone in the opposite case
okay
the second one is equal highs and equal
lows okay we have that same push to the
downside and the market pulls back
towards the supply Zone and what it
starts doing
starts doing like a little consolidation
forming equal highs and also equal lows
at the bottom okay so what does that
mean is that the market is prepping for
something and again if you just think
logically people are here seeing a
triple top what are they gonna do
they're gonna try to sell the market
because they think it's ready where is
their stop loss gonna be just above what
does the market do manipulates above
their stop loss Taps into the actual
supply and demand zone right and then it
dumps and where is the Target the first
Target is of course the equal lows that
are uh like the next opposite liquidity
Target and the next one is going to be
the weak low
okay so those are equal highs and equal
lows and the final one is very simple
this is like what you're gonna see
happening a lot you have like an old
high somewhere on the left right and
then the market does all sort of fun
stuff right this is where you can
actually be looking to launch the market
because we're in a push pullback right
and then the market attacks that high
takes out the weak high but then what
you're a lot of times what you're gonna
see is that the market then massively
drops lower and creates a trend change
and as I told you you cannot spot
liquidity
before it has actually happened right
you cannot say oh this high is liquidity
and after the market takes it out it's
going to reverse no because then to me
here the market is actually making a
structure break and what I'm going to be
doing is I'm gonna be looking to take a
long from right there but then if the
market makes a trend change in the
opposite direction that is when I can
say all right we took out the old high
we made the liquidity Gap we created the
trend change and that is when I'm
actually ready to go short
okay so those are the uh highs and lows
liquidity examples those are the three
types that I use my favorite one being
the inducement one and the equal highs
and lows because again with the singular
one right there I am not going to be
considering this a liquidity graph until
we make a trend change so this is a very
important point for you to to note so
let's have a look at some examples
there is one and I think we have uh yeah
we pretty much have all of those at one
place so what we have right there is if
I just grab my laser because I had some
hopefully you can see this right so here
we have a major High
right and then the market massively
dumped lower its overall bearish we
created like a pullback so what is this
right there this is I would say flat
liquidity this is flat price action
right but again within the flat price
action you're also going to have like a
major low which is right there okay
while the market does it comes in and
like spot how it got taken look at that
massive Wick so the market came in lots
of Rejection it just filled in the wick
and then after taking out the slow we
just massively expand it so this is
again a great uh type of like a
liquidity graph where you have like flat
price action takes it out and then
massively reverse higher where does it
go towards this massive major this is an
old old high right what happens after we
take out the note High well we get a
reaction right and we had a very nice
push to the downside what is this it's a
higher low do we get a long from here
absolutely where is our Target the week
high we come in we take out the week
high beautiful okay and what you can see
right there is that again if I just get
my drawing to to is that this time I
would be saying that this is a structure
break this is my demand Zone and I'm
potentially going to be looking too long
from here but again in hindsight what we
can see is that the market took out this
high and then caused the trend change
and after this I can say well okay then
this old high got taken and it caused
the reversal so that right there was a
liquidity grab and this is why I don't
love uh old highs and lows because we
don't know if it's going to be a
liquidity gap or if again it's just
going to be a breaker structure pullback
high low formation and a continuation
higher right
what we can see right there very flat so
equal lows on the bottom and equal highs
on the top what happens is the market
takes out the equal lows right and then
what it does it forms a trend change so
there is a structure break happening
right there in fact the train change
okay what caused the train change to
track it back it's this low so this is
technically our strong low where does
the market come in to retest a strong
low and then attacks the weak High okay
so you can see it's actually Market
structure but right now we combine
Market structure with liquidity this is
probably also the Asian range looking at
it this is probably the Asian range we
took it out we reversed to the upside we
pull back higher low information and
then we're pumping up right now so very
very very very simple let's have a look
at another example
there it is so this is on the one minute
right and I want to show you here the
inducement highs and lows okay so this
is a 50 minute demand Zone the market
has pushed up and I can see right there
that we have a 50 minute structure break
okay and look at what the market does it
pulls back it forms a little low and it
gives you a pullback so what happens
right there is that fomo Traders they're
gonna start going long so they are long
right there look at the candle there
were people that bought from there where
is their stop loss
below right there
the market dumps and takes out their
stop loss what happens again next is we
push up and what we actually get right
there is a fake Trend change which we're
going to cover in a bit so what happens
right now is that people are looking to
take a long trade from here also you can
look at the Wicks there are there were
some bullish reactions right there and
then the market comes in and takes it
and actually Taps into the 50 minute
demand Zone what happens later right if
you're just patient to wait for the
actual Trend change after the liquidity
is grabbed what caused the trend change
it's this low the market pulls back Taps
the demand Zone which was a wick and
then gives you the take profit towards
the new weak high on the 15 minute okay
so that's a great example of inducement
highs and lows those are this low right
there and this low right there those are
single lows that are inducement why
because those lows right when the market
pushes away it makes people want to buy
they think oh it's reversing I'm gonna
buy oh it's reversing I'm gonna buy
right no liquidity hasn't been taken yet
and you still don't have
your 50 minute Zone
right so that is inducement
by no example there it is this one is a
slightly bit more complex one right but
you can see a good example right there
of a combination of liquidity what do we
have right there is a node High what do
we have right there is equal highs right
and look at how the market like created
this little range then we have usually
liquidity is going to be grabbed with
speed right but then you also later want
to see speed away from it okay liquidity
High which is a node high flat highs
right there the market took it out with
speed
right and then I want you to pay very
close attention right this is the low
that caused the break of the high it got
broken right there yes it's by a pipette
but according to me even a pipette is a
break so then what I do is I want to
take a short where do I take a short
well you can of course refine you can
take this as a supply Zone you can take
this is a supply Zone what I personally
did is I used the guns tool the gun box
right and you can enter anywhere within
50 of this whole manipulation range
right and what you can see is the market
started forming new liquidity it started
forming flat lows right there
it created this high this High what do
people do right there they try to sell
the market but for the aggressive
traders that don't know how to place
their stop loss right they're gonna
Place their stop loss above this area
instead of the major high right so this
is all internal this is the major high
this is the major low anything inside is
internal so if you take a trade your
stop loss should always go above or
below the major highs and lows and what
the market did it just came in took out
this High has a single high liquidity
inducement and then you just plummeted
right so this is another example of
singular highs and lows liquidity make
sure to study it back later
structural liquidity so this is uh I've
seen it a lot within like people
explaining it it's it's nice but it's
it's much simpler than you think so
structural liquidity those are just old
structural levels higher lows higher
highs lower highs and lower lows and or
supply and demand zones all right so the
the key to this is that many Traders
refine their zones way too much they do
not follow the current the current Trend
and they end up becoming the liquidity
to those levels here is an example right
so usually the market is going to push
up so let me grab my other two so that
you actually see better it's going to
push up down up down up down right and
this is the top from here we make a
trend change so immediately after the
trend change what do we have is a
bearish market okay but if I just grab
my my pen right now the mistake that
Traders do is that they still think the
market is bullish so they're gonna drop
a demand zone right there they're gonna
drop a demand zone right there right but
the market is bearish from here
okay so they're gonna take along from
here they're gonna where is their stop
loss probably below here they get stop
loss they're gonna say oh no the next
one is gonna hold there is the next one
they take along from here where is their
stop loss right there
then the market Taps again oh this is an
old one right I'm gonna take it from
here the third one is a charm it's gonna
work out the market gives you a reaction
and then it drops and usually you're
gonna see uh in my videos that I code
those areas reaction points because
those old supply and demand zones they
act as of course a supply and demand but
they're just a reaction right you're
always gonna see like this demand Zone
it gave you a response this demand Zone
it gave you a response right this demand
Zone it also gave you a response but
when do you know that actually the
market is ready
simple when you get a trend change the
market is now bullish right and what
happens is the flip right so you flip
and right now what you have is demand
demand demand but what a lot of people
make a mistake is to still look at the
Supply right Supply gives you a reaction
breaks Supply gives your reaction breaks
Supply right those are the old levels
right that we were drawing
and they usually are going to give you a
response then the market is going to
take out the major high again guys going
back to Market structure and Trends this
is your push
this is your push this is your complex
pullback this is your push right so you
just gotta Master liquidity within those
ranges so let me give you an example all
right this is another one this is when
you're taking quite a few losses before
the trade actually moves in your
direction right and usually you're gonna
see it like this there is your hard time
frame Zone
and then what the market does it
actually starts to initiate away from it
and what it does it makes structure
right lower high lower low consolidates
lower high lower low consolidates lower
high lower low right and then what do
you do is instead of waiting for your
Zone to tap instead of waiting for the
market to get above 50 so you can take a
high probability trade you try to chase
it
and then this is your last supplies when
you take a trade from here you get a
stopless you're gonna be like okay no
that's gonna want to hold you take us
you take a trade from there stop loss
above you get a stop loss okay no this
is the last one that is gonna hold you
take a trade gives you a reaction stop
loss and this is when it actually Taps
into the Zone gives you the entry has
grabbed all the liquidity and then it
tends to run
okay so that is structural liquidity
those are old lower highs and again
remember within every lower high or a
higher low respectively there is going
to be supply and demand Zone
right so again do not draw old supply
and demand zones or structural levels
flow with the current flow of the market
there's an example uh yeah just study it
but again you can see like what is the
market doing right there it has a major
Harlow it has a major higher high this
is probably like a lower time frame
chart right so this is a probably
somewhere there is the major Harlow the
market has pushed away right so since
right here the market broke higher then
it broke lower we are bearish
so you can take a short here you can
take a short here you can take a short
here where pullback but the mistake you
do is you're like okay the market is
going to reverse from this demand Zone
oh it's gonna reverse from this demand
zone or it's going to reverse from this
demand Zone the market blasts through
this month blast through this one gave a
reaction Blaster gave a reaction blast
through until it actually stopped it
turned bullish precisely right there and
this is where you start longing the
market and then again you make the same
mistake ah this is Supply on the left
reaction stop loss also plan the left
reaction stop loss right there is a
supply on the left it gave you a
reaction right but this reaction just
gave you a long setup right there and
then it just blasted through it oh
Supply right there gave a reaction
blasted threat where is the liquidity
above the major High rather which is of
course weak so hopefully this makes
sense and it's kind of starting to uh
to show you some mistakes that you're
doing right trying to look too much on
the left trying to pick the right
reversal area while all you have to do
is just follow the market and follow the
recent structure and know that all of
these old areas like as soon as this
trend change happened right there and
the market turned bullish in alignment
with the overall trend all of these are
invalid all of these are going to give
you a reaction but eventually they're
going to get taken because the market is
bullish on the hard time
okay there's another example right you
have a hard time frame Zone but you want
to refine way too much you literally
want to catch the bottom right demands
on here here here here here here plenty
of demand zones I want you to study what
happens reaction stop loss reaction stop
loss reaction right A lot of people are
looking to buy from here stop loss
another reaction with a trend change
stop loss right then it came in again so
again
don't look at those levels on the left
what you simply have to do is wait for
the liquidity to be grabbed right wait
for that hard time frame Zone to fully
tap and wait for the price action to
develop within that area
right because if you try to pick all of
these structural uh zones and supply and
demand zones you're gonna fail because
those are liquidity okay
so more examples of that later on a live
chart
the next one is a fake TC paid charge
this is very simple right you just get a
trend change and it doesn't hold you get
a stop loss and then usually the next
one is gonna work right why does this
work and why is this liquidity well
because this tricks Traders into buying
or selling before the liquidity is
actually taken okay is there a way to
know uh what is a real Trend change or
what is a fake yes there is yes there is
right and this is also part of my
strategy a fake TC we always wait for
fake to see if of course other liquidity
hasn't been grabbed yet there is an
example right in this case we tap into
our zone right but guess what liquidity
hasn't been taken yet and the market
makes a trend change so this is where
all the people are going along long long
long long long long long where is their
stop loss below they get taken and this
is where we get the trend the real Trend
change with the real momentum right and
in this case you could have entered from
here but this is the most recent higher
low this is the major Harlow right there
with stock liquidity on top with stock
liquid on the bottom the market TAPS in
right there and then gives you the take
profit
capes do we have some liquidity here
some liquidity right there Taps into the
major Harlow and continues to go on
right so great example of fake Trend
change there's another one right
so the market Taps into the demand this
is still a lower low lower high lower
low the market gives you a trend change
and that is where you can start to enter
right to enter from right there but the
market tries to push and it fails to
take out the the high okay then it
retraces all the way back down you can
still look to enter here okay you enter
right there the market still gives you a
reaction but again remember liquidity
hasn't been grabbed yet
okay and then while the market does
comes in takes out the stop losses below
this area and then again gives you the
real Trend change at the bottom gets you
the entry and then goes on and hits take
profit
okay so in this case this trend change
was fake it got taken right there and
after it got taken here what we simply
have to wait for is for the next Trend
change to occur and then we take our
trade so very very very simple approach
and very powerful
the next one is flat highs and lows
liquidity very simple very
straightforward the only difference you
have to to make here is uh
is the direction of those flat highs and
lows right so this is a very simple it's
flat but it's a little bit subjective
because like sometimes the market can be
moving amazingly but it could be a
little bit flat right so it's slowly
moving corrective in nature it's making
structure but it's very choppy and this
is where you usually have like the trend
line liquidity and depending on the
direction of the trade it can either be
used as inducement or it can be used for
targets okay so I have a couple of
examples right there how we can look at
liquidity this way so here we have a
trend change
this is our major Harlow this is where
we want to take a long trade and then
the market usually does this this is
what I call in my uh Community The
Runaway setup The Runaway type of
liquidity which we're not going to be
covering in this lesson and this is
pretty much again lot lows what is flat
lows it's liquidity it's inducement
right so what the market does it like
Stacks it Stacks it Stacks it Stacks
then you have a sharp move tapping into
your demand zone right so the liquidity
right there it has been taken and then
you get the real move
okay so this type of liquidity is used
as inducement because it makes people
buy from here buy from here buy from
here where is their stop loss below they
got taken and then we run okay
so this is the flat lows when they're
used as uh inducement and in this
example we have plot highs that are used
for targets right because again we're
looking to long on this Market we have
all the confluences this is where we
want to enter and what happens is that
the market starts stacking lower highs
and lower lows against us what does this
make people do it makes them short short
where is their stop loss above so when
we actually get an entry you're going to
see an impulsive reaction and where is
the target of course above the flat high
so this right now is not inducement this
is flat High which is used for targets
okay and then the next one is like a
double manipulation we see this
happening very often right you have a
range the market takes out the high it
takes out the low right so liquidity
collected on top liquidity collected on
the bottom and then it's usually going
to go in the direction right so this is
very tricky to trade and I do not advise
trading this okay takes out the high
takes out the low then wait for the real
direction to be introduced wait for that
Trend changer structure break and then
just simply wait for the correction and
the market to impose okay so that is
flat highs and flat loads liquidity
there's an example right I think we had
a look at this example it was from one
of the hard time from charts we had
right so you can see here we have a base
Supply sellers are entering here sellers
are entering here seriously entering
here right but we also have a little bit
of a demand going on right there buyers
enter their buyers enter their bars
enter there what happens that the market
takes out all the buyers so everybody
got a stop loss right there in this flat
price action and then where are with the
next Target right so this is pretty much
that double liquidation right taking out
the low and then taking out the high
okay so when you see price action like
this compressing be prepared and usually
it's gonna get taken as I previously
mentioned with a lot of speed a lot of
speed taken and usually then it's going
to follow with a slight period of
consolidation where you can get your
entry and then a sharp move outside
okay
there's another example this is very
choppy very very very flat right so what
you have right there is just the pure
consolidation but again what I want you
to to look at is the details okay so we
have uh let me just grab the other laser
pointer we have the high we have the low
push pullback demand is forming on the
bottom demand here demand there but
people are seeing Supply and resistance
resistance so sellers here buyers here
sellers here buyers here what happens is
the market comes in stop losses takes
the stop loss of the sellers right then
the buyer so if I just illustrate them
the buyers are entering right there with
a breakout where is their stop loss
below right there right the market comes
in takes out their stop loss and then it
launches in the next Direction and then
you can see it drops again so what we
have right there is that double
manipulation we had an overall range
right the market accumulated stop loss
at the bottom stop loss at the top then
it made a massive manipulative move
higher and then massively dropped lower
so this is probably news but again you
get the point this is according to me
like flat price action right there
it forms some sort of structure but not
as much
okay
the next concept is a liquidity Gap okay
so this is pretty much uh a liquidity
Gap is uh
is also called sweep stop hunt
liquidation manipulation it doesn't
matter but it's a stop hunt right which
is simply a break of any liquidity point
that we just covered
okay so a liquidity Gap takes liquidity
and then launches the orders in the
opposite side and again as I told you
usually after a liquidity grab price
will sharply reject and reverse and
liquidity grab should always be followed
by a large influx of momentum okay so if
you get a liquidity Gap but then like
the market is not moving which you're
usually gonna see after a fake TC right
or maybe even an inducement taking out
the low if there is no liquidity then
you gotta wait a little bit more like
let's say for example
we got like a say we got we got a demand
Zone the market has pushed away we're
coming back down and then the market
like starts to form this takes out equal
lows but then it does this
right and maybe even cause the trend
change so do you think this liquidity
grab below right there is strong
no why because it's still building this
flat loads and usually what happens
takes them all out then it makes you the
momentum push and that is when you get
the trade okay so if you don't have
momentum after liquidity Gap then you
are probably going to become the
liquidity okay so wait for momentum and
again uh the stop Count those are the
BFI launching their fake orders in order
to take out of the Trader's stop losses
right and then usually they're gonna go
so a liquidity wrap is actually a very
good place to enter trades right it can
be retested but it should not break
because again if you have that same
scenario of the previous lesson if you
have a range
the market makes a massive buy and then
it sells off right so this is your flat
highs flat lows manipulation this is the
fake move okay so this is where the
banks both in order to sell they are
going to come back to retest to close
the orders but very rarely they're gonna
break above the zone right so if you
actually spot a liquidity graph okay it
is a very good place to enter your
trades place the stop loss above and you
are good to go okay
and again liquidity graphs are in all
time frames the concept is also fractal
you can have liquidity gaps on the
weekly daily one minute 15 seconds right
again you just need to systematize it
and keep it on the time frames that
you're using so a liquidity gap on a
hard time frame like the footage or the
50 minute will signify that a strong
zone is created right so if you have
like a supply and demand Zone that was
made by a liquidity graph it's very
strong what I mean by this is again
similar example you have like a
a downtrend the market makes a little
range sell to buy right so you have
right now a trend change you have a
demand Zone that was made by grabbing
liquidity below flat lows right so this
is a very strong Zone created if we come
back right there the chance of us
pushing higher is Big okay and also
liquidity got on a lower time frame
which is the one minute permit this
signifies liquidation which stops out
early buyers and sellers understanding
liquidity can increase your win rate by
a lot because if you just wait for the
liquidity to be grabbed when it comes to
your entries right your win rate is
going to increase Okay so
make sure to also include liquidity
graphs in your plan therefore so decide
on which liquidity points you're going
to be using after this lesson Right add
them to your strategy and then again
always wait for the liquidity map else
you will become the liquidity so if
you're getting a lot of stop losses if
you are having those situations in which
you take one loss two losses three
losses and then the market moves in your
direction right or you get a stop loss
then the market just massively
deployments in your direction then you
are not utilizing liquidity in the right
way okay so right now we're just going
to jump on the charts of course there
are some other additional Concepts on
liquidity one of my favorite one is the
Asian range I have already a video on
that right so we have like the daily
profiles as well usually like uh the
Asian say the Asian station highly the
London Station high and low they're
going to be becoming liquidity so that
is also other types of liquidity that
I'm covering in the program and we also
we have the Asian range which we have
four profiles so again make sure to
check out my Asian range video which is
going to expand a little bit more on
your really quick the understanding so
right now I just want to go into charts
show you a couple of examples show you
how you can actually train your eyes to
spot liquidity and hopefully it's gonna
make sense so you can go on your own and
practice identifying liquidity
all right so we are on the charts right
now and I'm gonna try to show you how
you can potentially spot liquidity I'm
first gonna start with a stop loss I
just took because I was a victim of
liquidity and now actually following
what I teach so let me start with that
and then I'm gonna show you some some
good examples so today I took a long on
your USD right and on the party time
frame we are a little bit High okay so
I'm not looking on the left what is
happening on the left right I'm just
focusing on what is happening right now
but I was mainly focused on the 50
minutes so today was a great example of
taking out an old high which is also
known as previous daily High okay so
this is also a form of liquidity right
which is considered an old high right
which is the previous daily high so in
this case this was the previous daily
high this was also paired with the Asian
high which is also liquidity right this
is also paired with liquidity that is
resting just in the opposite direction
like look at this flat price action this
is all flat price action right this is
all potentially gonna get taken so what
happens is on uh
around Frankfurt open the market does
this okay but again according to me what
I told you like one of the drawbacks uh
with the way I trade is that I follow
structure according to me again at that
time this was not a liquidity grab this
to me was again a continuation but I was
aware and I also shouted this in my
morning analysis we took that trade it
was a stop loss which is fine but again
we took out previous daily High we took
out Asian high with lots of momentum
that could lead graph happened with lots
of momentum we consolidate it for a
little bit and then we just started
dropping but I also want to show you how
I also waited for an extra liquidity
okay there is my uh demand Zone what did
I told you what did I tell you about
that liquid on the Left Right drawing
this demand Zone the market reacting
flushing drawing this demand Zone
the market reacting flushing okay so
what I was looking for is for this to be
taken what we also had what is this guys
right so this is a trend change
right so this according to me was a fake
Trend change what is this this is flat
price action right there right the
market pushed up and then it just
started massively rolling down and I set
it in the community this one is gonna
reverse okay but still a setup is a
setup okay we drop the liquidity of the
fake TC we grab the liquidity of that
structural liquid on the left and if you
really zoom in right there this is where
we got our actual TC and the trade was
taken from here some of my members place
the stop loss below I personally below
like the major Zone I personally place
it right there and that was a pretty
quick stop loss right why well because
the market grabbed macro liquidity right
and it was gonna retrace on the way back
down okay but you can see how I waited
for the structure liquidity to be taken
for the fake TC and also for these flat
lows okay so this trade was valid
according to me because I had all the
liquidity graph
um rules ticked okay so this is one way
you can practice is liquidity okay you
can
go on your charts and have a look what
happens after we take out major Keys
what do we have what does happen after
we take out major lows right like let's
have a look at the previous day right
there what we have is an overall bullish
Market okay where is our old high it's
right there so we can later explore like
what happens we get a pullback but then
we still continue to push higher okay so
look what happens right there what is
this type of price action right here
it's very flat okay and not only that
it's very flat but it's also the Asian
range so again liquidity is going to be
below the Asian low right and of course
below all of these flat lows right there
so for example all of this right there
is flat and you can see where the flat
price action starts this is where we
came in to take it out okay so
technically what happens is we went on
to retest this Zone
which is the zone that potentially
formed the quality higher low formation
so this is more advanced I call this
tcobs right this is a bit more advanced
we tap them right there okay so
liquidity has been grabbed below the
Asian range liquidity has been taken
here liquidity has been taken there okay
but this is the 15 minute time frame so
what I want you to do is to draw 50
minute zones or flowery zones and then
drop to a time frame lower to actually
see what is happening okay so right
there I'm gonna drop on the one minute
what do we have just before we tap the
zone
right we have
lot loss right flat lows but this hasn't
even tapped The Zone massively pushing
to the downside what is this it's
potential liquidity Gap but again
uh I have a very important rule right
that liquidity should not happen like I
have specific percentages right there
where you should be looking for
liquidity Gap right I'm not going to be
sharing here here we're focused on just
liquidity okay what happens right here
we tap into the zone and what do we make
we make a trend change okay so what
happens right there is that there are
buyers entering this Market is this
trade valid yes right but to me it's not
because to me like this is not liquidity
to me okay the market pushes up is that
it actually gives you a 3r if you're
looking for a quick trade you can hit TP
but what happens later is the market
actually forms like these flat lows we
have a fake train change liquidity gap
which happened precisely right there so
what you just have to wait later
is for a new trend change and what you
can see immediately on the opposite side
happening is you have a little bit of a
trend line okay you have flat tops
happening right there in the opposite
direction which is always good for
profit taking we took out the low what
cause to take out the low it was this so
this is where we made the trend change
precise on this candle what caused the
train change well pretty much is this
big cell right you can see as I told you
liquidity gaps are always going to
happen with momentum massive sell-off
immediate reaction caused the train
change and you can be looking to enter
on this bearish candle stop loss below
and then the trade
the trade should usually go right and
where does it go towards the Asian high
right so you can see what happens after
you take out Asian high
we we go down right this is the pretty
much the liquidity grab this is the
recharge mechanism creates a high low
and then it continues to go up okay so
this is pretty much how you can practice
again this depends on your time frame so
you need to do all the work coming uh
onto this video so right now you can
actually practice doing this here's
another example right the market is
bullish cool where is our valid 50
minute range it's right there why is it
right there well zoom in where is our
last break of structure it's right there
what caused the last break of structure
it's this
swing low make it blue swing High okay
anything inside is internal we don't
care but what is happening right here is
we have massive flat highs forming as a
Target and we have massive flat lows
right there forming us potential
liquidity right I tend to form the flat
loads with with this kind of tool it's
the what's it called the Curve
right you can see here what we have is a
squeeze
what does the market do Trends down
pulls back massive sharp push wear into
our demand Zone where taking this old
low
right so this is the liquidity graph
what happens later a massive pump let's
see on the one minute right so now we go
into one minute what do you do
let's see if we have some liquidity grab
right there what is so this right there
we are already tapping into the zone
right what do we have right here is a
trend change
is this the real Trend change
I don't know
right you gotta you gotta practice to
start identifying which is fake which is
real okay this is the first train change
that occurred right there is no train
change here there is no train change
train change anywhere this is the first
one that occurred is this valid no
because it's too early it's below it's
still uh within Asia and liquidity
hasn't been grabbed yet
what do we also have is that fake Trend
change combined with all of this fraud
price action what happens the market
massively comes in down
everything is collected Asian low blood
liquidity low fake Trend change old
liquidity low so you have a very high
probability chance right now that the
Mark is gonna rock it what you have to
Simply wait for is for the market to
give you the signal
chain change right find your Zone to
enter there is your trade stop loss
always goes below right there and then
of course where you can Target is Asian
high or you can of course go towards the
new major high and you nail a pretty
nice trade
okay so hopefully is starting to make
sense right so this is pretty much how I
practice because you wanna systematize
this you don't just want to go and say
oh
range flat highs oh we took the
liquidity right and then we massively
roll down that's perfect okay but how do
you enter okay so I want you to zoom in
right there and say okay well let's see
we had all of these flat highs they got
taken right there so let's but again at
this point this is wrong to do because
this was a push and like our major
Harlow was right there so we were
technically bullish at that time but at
that top you can go and explore the top
okay let me just go and check out the 15
minutes okay what's happening on the 50
minutes well let's see we have a massive
run up where is my major high low
formation it's right there
okay let's see what happens right there
so this is our demand Asian range
perfect the market comes in Taps into
the area so right here you can go on and
spot okay do we have liquidity well we
have Asian low which is cool okay is the
market bullish yes it is right so the
highlighter is here the major high is
there major low right so right here what
you can go and do is you can drop to the
50 minute or first you can at least so
for example this is where later we had a
trend change
okay let's try and change down what
caused the trend change right there it's
this guy right and this is where
actually we got the short later on right
so you can see here we have an old high
liquidity which got taken so let's go
and explore right
oh we can't go all the way back down all
right all right so so that's a Pity
because that would have been a great
example right but you get the point
right where is this okay this is a
little bit far away so we can't get
right there right but what you have to
do right now is go right here on the one
minute and see that the market first
stopped right there it made a fake TC
and then it came in and took it out
right there right then it gave you the
real TC and probably you got a stop loss
right and that's fine then the market
reverses down it pulls back do you have
any liquidity graphs within this area
right this is what you gotta check okay
so pretty much that's it okay this is
how I practice you can first start with
the with the following time frame right
you can draw flowery zones but again I
really love doing this on the 15 minute
because the 50 minute offers you plenty
of opportunity to to do so all right so
for example uh let me just one final one
okay final one so uh let's check out
here so here we are bullish on the phone
time frame but the market made a trend
change right there unfortunately did not
pull back then it made another uh
structure break here and then it made a
15 minute train change up there what
caused the train change it's this
unfortunately we did not tap
then we get another structure okay this
is a tough example I did this yesterday
yeah I we didn't get any trades
yesterday but again you gotta go and
explore it so there is a supply zone
right here
right and then there is a demand zone
right there so let's see if we can could
have gotten into any trades
okay so there is a supply Zone
and uh yeah so we can see right there
the market so if I just move this away
the market tapped inside the Zone what
did it create it create a trend change
right is it fake yes why because
liquidity hasn't been grabbed what does
the market do later it comes in begs the
train change why is this right there on
the left
oh that's your structural supply and
demand liquidity what happens with it it
gets taken the market reacts and then
goes on and takes it okay so after this
is collected then you can be looking to
take your short which eventually got a
stop loss then we look at it on the
other side right and in this case uh
yeah the market didn't even tap the zone
so we don't get any trade and then we
can look at this guy right there okay so
let's see what happens
the market TAPS in what do we have first
is we have
one of these structured you could do
what happens is there are buyers
entering from right there where is their
stop loss it's below right there what
happens they get taken what is this
right there oh it's a trend change okay
where are people going to be entering
from right there they get a reaction and
then they get a stop loss
okay then where is the next train change
that occurred right here
or you can even say right there right
and then after all the liquidity is
collected this liquidity Gap fake Trend
change there is the real one with clean
momentum right there right then you got
the retest right and then the market I
think that was the ooh yeah that was the
the CPI so we don't trade at that time
but you can see that it doesn't matter
what the time is when the liquidity is
grabbed when the concepts align you get
your trade okay so those are pretty much
some examples and some guidelines on how
to to practice this if you have
questions or if you need more examples
let me know in the comments and I'm
going to be making a separate video all
right Fanatics hopefully you enjoyed the
liquidity lesson you got a lot from it
you learned the different types of
liquidity we had a look at the charts
and you know what to do from now on it's
important go on your charts back test
see how it works and start working on
your trading plan and actually from this
lesson adding liquidity Concepts into
your trading plan and to all the
knowledge that you have accumulated so
far within Market structure it's a plan
Demand right now we add liquidity to the
to the to the kind of to the toolbox and
up next we have entries how to enter
trades like a pro for both swing and day
trades all right so stay tuned for the
next one make sure you're subscribed
turn on the notification Bell on in
order not to miss the updates and again
the main thing you can do for me is to
subscribe hit the like button so that I
actually know that you're liking the
video leave a comment below and let me
know if you need more examples if you
have any questions I'm always here for
you in the comments so ask questions I
love hearing them and I can't wait to
see you on the next video wishing you a
crushing trading week a crushing trading
performance and hopefully all the
concepts are already doing the work and
you're having results